

Shrikrishna Ramanbainwad

Engineer(Data Scientist) I am a passionate Data Scientist with 3.5 years of experience, Having knowledge of Machine learning, Deep learning, RNN, CNN, NLP, Fundamentals of MLOps, ML/DL model building and Always eager to learn and explore new things.

MY CONTACT

- 🔀 shri.bainwad100cr@gmail.com
- **(**) +91 -9975019031/7066337306
- Near Krishna Temple Golegaon pk, Loha, Nanded 431714
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/shrikrishnaramnbainwad-a31233166/
- https://github.com/Shri-ds100cr?tab=stars
- https://medium.com/@shri.bainwad100cr

SKILLS

- Python, Numpy, Pandas, Data Visualization
- Data Analysis & Data Preprocessing
- Exploratory Data Analysis(EDA), Microsoft Excel
- Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision
- NLP, Flask, Streamlit, API, SQL, MLOPS, Power BI, BERT
- Statistics Modeling & Statistics Analysis
- Google Cloud, AWS, Azure

Technical Expertises

- Programming Languages:- Python
- Packages: NumPy,Pandas, SciKit-learn, NLTK, Keras Matplotlib, TensorFlow, OpenCV, SciPy, Seaborn, NLTK
- Tools: -Jupiter, VScode, Google Colab, Spyder, Git, Pycharm
- Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, K-Means, Naive Bayes, Support Vector Machine, Random Forest And XGBOOST
- Deep Learning Modeling: ANN, CNN, RNN, LSTM, NLP, Object Detection, Encoder-Decoder, YOLO

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering Pune University | 2014-2018, 73%

Extracurricular Activities

- Six Times Blood and Two Times Platelets Donar
- University Chess Player, Volunteer activities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tech Mahindra | April 2021 - Now

Engineer(Data Scientist)

Project Title: Casting defect detection using CNN to reduce inspection time.

Tools and Techniques:

• Python, Tensorflow, Keras, CNN

Description:

• We Build a Deep learning model to reduce inspection time in the casting process by using a CNN to detect casting defects. The CNN will be trained on a dataset of images of defective and Non-defective castings and classify whether given image is defective or non defective

Project Title: Wafer Fault Detection using Machine Learning

Tools and Techniques:

• Python, Random Forest, Xg Boost, GridSearch

Description:

• We Build a Machine learning model using Random forest and XgBoost algorithms. The goal is to build model which predicts whether a wafer needs to be replaced or not(i.e., whether it is working or not) based on the inputs from various sensors. There are two classes: +1 and -1.

Tata Technology | March 2019-Sep 2020

Project Title: Lane detection and Identification using Deep Learning

Tools and Techniques:

• Python, CNN, RNN, Keras

Description:

• This CNN model is used to detect the path for selfdriving cars and to avoid the risk of getting in another lane.

Personal Projects

Future Sales prediction (Time Series Analytics)

• Time series analysis done using Facebook Prophet

Customer Segmentation using machine learning

• Built using K-Means Clustering algorithm

Credit card fraud detection using Machine Learning

• This Model Built using Logistic Regression Algorithm

Developed a ChatBot for desktop Application

Achievements

• Received " Pat On Back "(POB) (2022) and "Spot Award" (2021) at Tech Mahindra.

Certifications

- Cloud Technical Series participation Certificate by Google
- Machine & Deep Learning by cognitive class (IBM)
- NLP, SQL, Statistics And Six Sigma by "Udemy"
- Google Cloud platform & Cloud Computing by Simplilearn
- **Aws** Certificates by Great Learning
- Azure Fundamental and Azure Services by Simplilearn